exchangeserverpro.com 2019-07-02

# Privacy Policy

Last Updated: September 24th, 2018

This web site is owned and operated by Quadrotech Solutions AG and will be referred to as “We”, “our” and “us” in this Internet Privacy Policy. By using this site, you agree to the Internet Privacy Policy of this web site (“the web site”), which is set out on this web site page. The Internet Privacy Policy relates to the collection and use of personal information you may supply to us through your conduct on the web site.

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to modify or remove portions of this Internet Privacy Policy at any time. This Internet Privacy Policy is in addition to any other terms and conditions applicable to the web site. We do not make any representations about third party web sites that may be linked to the web site.

We recognise the importance of protecting the privacy of information collected about visitors to our web site, in particular information that is capable of identifying an individual (“personal information”). This Internet Privacy Policy governs the manner in which your personal information, obtained through the web site, will be dealt with. This Internet Privacy Policy should be reviewed periodically so that you are updated on any changes. We welcome your comments and feedback.

### **Personal Information**

Personal information about visitors to our site is collected only when knowingly and voluntarily submitted. For example, we may need to collect such information to provide you with further services or to answer or forward any requests or enquiries. It is our intention that this policy will protect your personal information from being dealt with in any way that is inconsistent with applicable privacy laws.

### **What Personal Information We Collect and Why**

#### **Email Subscriptions**

When visitors opt-in to our email newsletter we collect the personal information that is shown in the email opt-in form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

#### **Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the personal information shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here:  _[https://automattic.com/privacy/](https://automattic.com/privacy/?__hstc=18650278.56a71d666b4c81b3819962ab6327b961.1536232198680.1537356302791.1537370401286.30&__hssc=18650278.2.1537370401286&__hsfp=1148909922)_. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

If you opt-in to be notified by email when new comments appear on specific blog posts, your email address is collected so that comment notifications can be sent to you.

#### **Contact forms**

When visitors submit a contact form we collect the personal information shown in the contact form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

#### **Cookies**

Cookies are data that a Web site transfers to an individual's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies, which are industry standard and are used by most Web sites, including those operated by us, can facilitate a user's ongoing access to and use of a site. They allow us to customise the web site to your needs. If you do not want information collected through the use of Cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to deny or accept the Cookie feature. But you should note that Cookies may be necessary to provide you with some features of our on-line services.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal information and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal information and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

#### **Embedded Content from Other Websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect information about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

#### **Analytics**

This web site tracks particular aspects of you and other people who visit this web site. We currently use:

  * Google Analytics
  * Facebook Ads Tracking Pixel
  * HubSpot

This tracking is used to provide us with information about how people use this site, how our marketing campaigns are performing, and other information such as where in the world people are visiting from so that we can optimize content and performance to suit our audiences.

### **Use of Information**

Personal information that visitors submit to our site is used only for the purpose for which it is submitted or for such other secondary purposes that are related to the primary purpose unless we disclose other uses in this Internet Privacy Policy or at the time of collection. Copies of correspondence sent from the web site, that may contain personal information, are stored as archives for record-keeping and back-up purposes only.

### **How Long Do We Keep Your Personal Information?**

We keep your personal information for different periods of time, depending on why it was collected.

  * Opt-in to email newsletters – indefinitely. You can opt-out of emails by clicking the unsubscribe link that is included in each email. We also delete email lists that are no longer required, such as expired products or offers. Inactive subscribers are also removed from email lists at various times throughout the year.
  * Contact form submissions – entries are deleted from the database each December for the previous year. For example, in December 2018, the entries for the year 2017 will be deleted. The emails generated by the contact form are retained indefinitely in the recipient mailbox.
  * Comment subscriptions – indefinitely. You can opt-out of comment subscriptions by clicking the link that is included in each email.
  * Website comments – indefinitely.
  * Website backups – indefinitely. Personal information that may have been removed from the live website will still exist in website backups, which are stored indefinitely in secure, cloud-hosted storage.
  * Google Analytics – 38 months.

### **Disclosure**

Apart from where you have consented, or disclosure is necessary to achieve the purpose for which it was submitted, personal information may be disclosed in special situations where we have reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against anyone damaging, injuring, or interfering (intentionally or unintentionally) with our rights or property, users, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. Also, we may disclose personal information when we believe in good faith that the law requires disclosure.

We may engage third parties to provide you with goods or services on our behalf. In that circumstance, we may disclose your personal information to those third parties in order to meet your request for goods or services.

We currently use the following third parties that may require disclosure of your personal information in order to provide a service:

  * _[Google Analytics](https://privacy.google.com/businesses/compliance/?__hstc=18650278.56a71d666b4c81b3819962ab6327b961.1536232198680.1537356302791.1537370401286.30&__hssc=18650278.2.1537370401286&__hsfp=1148909922)_ – for tracking of usage of this website by visitors.
  * _[Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/business/gdpr?__hstc=18650278.56a71d666b4c81b3819962ab6327b961.1536232198680.1537356302791.1537370401286.30&__hssc=18650278.2.1537370401286&__hsfp=1148909922)_ – the Facebook Ads tracking pixel is used for audience targeting and to track performance of Facebook ad campaigns.
  * [HubSpot](https://www.hubspot.com/)– for tracking of usage of this website by visitors.

### **Security**

We strive to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of personal information submitted to our sites, and we review and update our security measures in light of current technologies. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure.

However, we will endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect the personal information you may transmit to us or from our online products and services. Once we do receive your transmission, we will also make our best efforts to ensure its security on our systems.

In addition, our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us. However, we will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to your personal information.

### **Access to Information**

We will endeavour to take all reasonable steps to keep secure any information which we hold about you, and to keep this information accurate and up to date. If, at any time, you discover that information held about you is incorrect, you may contact us to have the information corrected.

In addition, our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us.

### **Links to other sites**

We provide links to Web sites outside of our web sites, as well as to third party Web sites. These linked sites are not under our control, and we cannot accept responsibility for the conduct of companies linked to our website. Before disclosing your personal information on any other website, we advise you to examine the terms and conditions of using that Web site and its privacy statement.

### **Sale of Business**

If this business or web site is sold, your personal information will be an asset that is transferred to the new owner.

### **Problems or questions**

If we become aware of any ongoing concerns or problems with our web sites, we will take these issues seriously and work to address these concerns. If you have any further queries relating to our Privacy Policy, or you have a problem or complaint, please  _[contact us](https://practical365.com/contact)_.
